Guide to the News Clippings and Articles about Yale University
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
News clippings and articles about Yale University
1945-1986
RU 64
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2
The records consist of national-level newspaper and periodical articles, collected by a newsclipping service, concerning various aspects of Yale University.
Yale University. Office of Public Affairs
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-C (YRG 4-C), Records documenting public information functions of Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Existence and Location of Copies
Microfilm (HM 155) is arranged in two series: I: 1945-1974 (19 reels); II: 1974-1983 (5 reels).
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of national-level newspaper and periodical articles, collected by a newsclipping service, concerning various aspects of Yale University.
Universities and colleges -- Public relations; Yale University -- Public relations; Yale University. Office of Public Affairs
- Clippings [microfilm], 1945-1983; Accession 1983-A-030
  Scope and Contents
  HM 155
  - Clippings, 1945-1974; Series I
    - 1945 July 1 - 1946 June 30 (Box 1)
    - 1946 July 1 - 1947 June 30 (Box 1)
    - 1947 July 1 - 1948 June 30 (Box 1)
    - 1948 July 1 - 1949 June 30 (Box 1)
    - 1949 July 1 - 1950 June 30 (Box 1)
    - 1950 July 1 - 1951 June 30 (Box 2)
    - 1951 July 1 - 1952 June 30 (Box 2)
    - 1952 July 1 - 1953 June 30 (Box 3)
    - 1953 July 1 - 1954 June 30 (Box 4)
    - 1954 July 1 - 1955 June 30 (Box 5)
    - 1955 July 1 - 1956 June 30 (Box 5)
    - 1956 July 1 - 1957 June 30 (Box 6)
    - 1957 July 1 - 1958 June 30 (Box 6)
    - 1958 July 1 - 1959 June 30 (Box 6)
    - 1959 July 1 - 1960 June 30 (Box 7)
    - 1960 July 1 - 1961 June 30 (Box 7)
    - 1961 July 1 - 1962 June 30 (Box 7)
    - 1962 July 1 - 1963 June 30 (Box 8)
    - 1963 July 1 - 1964 June 30 (Box 8)
    - 1964 July 1 - 1965 June 30 (Box 9)
    - 1965 July 1 - 1966 June 30 (Box 10)
    - 1966 July 1 - 1967 June 30 (Box 11)
    - 1967 July 1 - 1968 June 30 (Box 12)
    - 1968 July 1 - 1968 December (Box 13)
    - 1969 January 1 - 1969 June 30 (Box 14)
    - 1969 July 1 - 1969 December 21 (Box 15)
    - 1970 January 1 - 1970 June 30 (Box 16)
    - 1970 July - 1971 June (Box 17)
    - 1971 July 1 - 1972 June 30 (Box 18)
    - 1972 July 1 - 1973 June 30 (Box 18)
    - 1973 July 1 - 1974 June 30 (Box 19)
  - Clippings, 1974-1983; Series II
    - 1974 May - 1976 June (Box 1)
    - 1976 July - 1977 (Box 2)
    - 1978 - 1979 (Box 3)
    - 1980 (Box 4)
    - 1981 - 1983 March (Box 5)
- Clippings, 1980-1986; Accession 1986-A-078
  In boxes 1 - 4 the dates represent clippings dates.
  In boxes 5 - 7 the date represents the date the packet of clippings was compiled.
  - Articles Dated 1980-1981
    - 1980 January 4 - February 14; 1980 February 13-28 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
    - 1980 February 29-April 24; 1980 March 25-April 14; 1980 April 9-15; 1980 April 19-May 6; 1980 May 8-19; 1980 May 21-January 1 (Box 2, Folder 8-14)
    - 1980 June 1-July 14; 1980 July 18-October 3; 1980 October 5-November 7 (Box 3, Folder 15-21)
    - 1980 November 7-December 1; 1981 November 25-February 11; 1981 February 10-March 2; 1981 March 6-April 10; 1981 April 9-November 12 (Box 4, Folder 22-27)
  - Articles Compiled 1982-1986
    - 1982 February 6-March 26; 1982 April 13-July 8; 1982 July 7-November 1; 1982 October 21-1983 May 13 (Box 5, Folder 28-34)
    - 1983 May 31-November 28; 1983 December 7-1984 March 5; 1984 March 12-April 25; 1984 May 3-August 28; 1984 September 14-October 8 (Box 6, Folder 35-40)
    - 1984 October 22-November 5; 1984 December 6-12; 1985 January 8-27; 1985 February 7-March 7; 1985 March 19-April 12; 1985 April 23-May 21; 1985 June 10-August 21; 1985 September 12-October 21; 1985 November 19-1986 January 3 (Box 7, Folder 41-49)
- Scrapbook documenting individuals at Yale, circa 1975-1976; Accession 2004-A-067
  - Scrapbook, circa 1975-1976 (Box 1)